Jaco van Cranenburgh

Richmond, Surrey mail@jaco.site 07719975115

I am a hardworking software developer with an Upper Second Class Honours BSc Computer Science Degree. Keen to learn, adapt and improve my technical skills through a career. I have been very interested in computing since I was young, and over the last 7 years have become passionate about programming and moving forward into a software development career.

DOB: 9th August 1996 Gender: Male Nationality: British/Dutch

Technical Skills

HTML/CSS Java JavaScript Node.js C# ASP.net Python **IT Support**

SQL AWS Lambda/Beanstalk

Education

2014 - 2018 2.1 Degree:

University of Portsmouth | I completed a 4-year BSc degree (including 1-year placement) **BSc Hons Computer Science** in Computer Science that covers many topics within the computing arena. It has given me technical skills such as programming in Java, Python, JavaScript and C# through units such as Advanced Programming Concepts and Software Engineering. Alongside this, it has given me a good theoretical understanding of many areas of Computer Science such as Data Structures, Networking, and Web Research.

> Completing the degree has developed and enhanced my skills in:

- Group work, being able to take charge when needed.
- Conducting research, investigating paper and other resources on relevant topics.
- Expressing myself verbally and speaking in front of an audience.
- Working independently on projects and managing my time effectively.

2012 - 2014 A-Levels:

Richmond College

- Computing (C)
- Use of Maths (B)
- **Graphics Communication (E)**

10 GCSEs including:

2006 - 2012 **Greycourt School**

- Maths (A)
- Science (A)
- English (C)

Relevant Experience

IT Support – University of Portsmouth, Sept 2017 – June 2018

Worked part-time for the University of Portsmouth as a member of the IT Support staff. This involved providing general IT Support in various University buildings such as the University Library and helping students, using my technical knowledge and problem-solving skills to resolve student IT problems. In cases where the problem could not be solved, it was my duty to refer them to the appropriate department or resources. Customer service was a large part of my role, ensuring that the students could get the help they needed, particularly around the end of term when a small IT problem could mean missing an important deadline.

Web Developer - Veritas Technologies, June 2016 - July 2017

Completed a 13-month placement year as part of my degree at Veritas Technologies. I worked as a web developer as part of an Agile team, where my role was to build and maintain an internal 'dashboard' website that tracked internal team performance statistics from data sources such as TFS and ETrack. This role included building windows services for data collection, maintaining an ASP.net website, designing, maintaining and deploying databases, and communicating with managers to determine requirements. My job involved a lot of independent work implementing new features and fixing bugs, which improved my ability to manage my own workload. Frequent team meetings and scrum stand-ups also allowed me to improve my communications skills and teamwork, especially when working alongside other developers for larger features.

Other Experience

Bartender – The Sun Inn, May – August 2015

Worked at the Sun Inn, Richmond as a Bartender. This job involved working behind the bar, serving food, cleaning tables and washing up in the kitchen. Working alongside a team of people helped me become more confident and taught me how to work under pressure when the bar was full. Working successfully as a team was vital in providing a fast and productive service for customers.

Support Worker/Carer, June - August 2014

For family with teenager with special needs. I accompanied their son on half day excursions to go swimming, dining and shopping on a regular basis. My commitment was to help and motivate him to get the most out of his day in terms of enjoyment, self-empowerment and creativity whilst ensuring his safety.

Personal

Personal interests within technology include permission-less and immutable cryptocurrencies, home server setups (with self-hosted applications), and technologies as a tool for social change.

Other interests include snowboarding, hiking and video games.

References available upon request.